Archana.G.S Data Scientist

Portfolio Linkedin Upwork Github Published paper

Milpitas,CA 669 231 9980 archanags001@gmail.com

Data Scientist with over 4 years of experience, specializing in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Demonstrated success in creating machine learning models, conducting in-depth data analysis, and applying problem-solving skills. Eager to contribute my expertise to the dynamic and challenging field of AI.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist — **Wonder Chrome** (December 2021 - PRESENT)

- Conducted A/B testing experiments to assess the effectiveness of various promotion strategies, resulting in a remarkable 24% increase in revenue.
- Developed machine learning models using scikit-learn to optimize pricing strategies, leading to a substantial 12% boost in profit.
- Led end-to-end data lifecycle from collection to dashboard/report creation using SQL, Python, and AWS Sagemaker.
- Developed a Large-scale multi-label text classification model using Tensorflow and Keras to enhance text analysis capabilities.
- Experience with OpenAI GPT models and API for enhancing natural language understanding and text generation tasks.

Data Scientist — Freelance (January 2019 - PRESENT) Upwork

- Top Rated freelancer, representing the top 10% of Upwork talent.
- Collaborated with 8 clients to understand their company needs and devise data-driven solutions.
- Optimized credit risk minimization models using Gurobi, improving loan allocation strategies while balancing profitability and regulatory compliance.
- Designed and developed a Gen AI News search tool leveraging LLM and Langchain technologies, and a vector database enhancing the efficiency of information retrieval and analysis.
- Developed custom AI solutions leveraging cloud services (Azure, AWS), working with Docker for seamless model deployment.

Artificial Intelligence Engineer intern —Uniquify Inc(August 2021-October 2021)

- Led training and development of neural networks using TensorFlow, optimizing models for enhanced accuracy and efficiency.
- Conducted comprehensive experiments with TensorFlow scripts and analyzed results to enhance model performance and understand framework dynamics.
- Played a key role in debugging and improving an automation framework for neural network and TensorFlow scripts, streamlining workflows and ensuring reliable model training.
- Developed advanced image processing and segmentation algorithms to solve complex problems, contributing to project success.

Data Analyst — Centriqe Inc (February 2020 - January 2021)

- Developed an NLP system using NLTK to automate text analysis, resulting in a significant 39% reduction in manual analysis efforts, improving efficiency.
- Leveraged analytical and technical expertise to provide actionable insights and proposals, driving business improvement strategies.
- Designed and implemented a range of predictive models, including classification and forecasting models, using various machine learning tools to solve complex business challenges.
- Identified trends, key metrics, and critical data points, generating insightful
 dashboards using a variety of data visualization tools to facilitate data-driven
 decision-making.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Python, R, Core Java, Basic JavaScript

Machine Learning and DeepLearning: TensorFlow, Keras, CNN, RNN, PyTorch

Natural Language Processing

(NLP): NLP techniques, Hugging Face, Langchain, Transfer learning,SpaCy, BeautifulSoup

Computer Vision: OpenCV, Transfer learning,YOLO, VGG16, ResNet

Generative AI: Gen AI,LLM, Langchain, Hugging Face, OpenAI, Gemini, LLAMA

Cloud Services: AWS, Azure

Database & Data Storage: SQL, MongoDB

Data Visualization Tools:

Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn

Big Data: PySpark

Dashboard Development:

Power BI, Tableau, Retool, Dash, Streamlit, Kibana

EDUCATION

Master of Technology in Electronics with specialization in Signal processing

GPA: 4.0

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication Engineering **GPA: 3.5**

WORK ELIGIBILITY:

EAD(Employment Authorization Document)